Divyansh Chandak

Systems Engineer

Profile

A motivated individual with in-depth knowledge of programming languages, development tools, and cloud computing and having 2.5 years of IT experience seeking a position in a growth-oriented company where I can use my skills to the advantage of the company while having the scope to develop my skills.

Employment History

Systems Engineer at Tata Consultancy Services, Gandhinagar, Gujarat

January 2024 — July 2024

Support Data Engineer

- Developed and maintained a data warehouse structure, enabling the business to make data-driven decisions and resulting in a 20% increase in operational efficiency.
- Implemented database backup and recovery processes, reducing system downtime by 50% and improving overall system reliability by 25%.
- Create and design interactive dashboards and visualizations using Tableau software
- Analyze and interpret complex data sets to identify trends, patterns, and insights
- Managed migration project from Azure blob storage to SQL server for datasets using Azure data factory
- Designed python modules using panda libraries to import and export data from SQL.
- Designed python scripts to manipulate the data on Tableau software.

Assistant Systems Engineer at Tata Consultancy Services, Gandhinagar, Gujarat

January 2022 — December 2023

SQL Developer

- Design, develop, and maintain databases and database objects, such as tables, views, stored procedures, and triggers
- Built an automated SQL server store procedure to perform daily ETL operations that saved 15 hours per week
- Managed and analyzed data sets using SQL resulting in a 10% increase in overall operation efficiency.
- Developed and optimized complex SQL queries resulting in increase in performance of 30+ systems.
- Monitor database performance and troubleshoot issues
- Develop and maintain data warehouse structures

Details

Gandhinagar, Gujarat India +91-9079140480 divyanshchandak1998@gmail.com

Date of birth

1 Sept 1998

Nationality

Indian

Skills

SQL

Python

Github

C Programming

Tableau

Linux

Data Structure and Algorithms

Azure

Azure Data Factory

Microsoft Power BI

Java

Languages

English

Hindi

Assistant Systems Engineer Trainee at Tata Consultancy Services, Gandhinagar, Gujarat

December 2021 — January 2022

- Training on Python and SQL programming.
- Trained on Agile methodology and SDLC processes

Education

BTech (ME), College of Technology and Engineering, Udaipur

August 2017 — September 2021

Graduated with 7.30 CGPA in Mechanical Engineering

12th, St Anthony Senior Secondary School, CBSE Affiliated, Udaipur

May 2015 — June 2016

- Majors in Science Maths
- Passed with 80.40%
- JEE Mains Qualifier

10th, St Anthony Senior Secondary School, CBSE Affiliated, Udaipur

May 2013 — June 2014

Passed with 7.8 CGPA

★ Certifications

Python Beginner Certification, Hackerrank

SQL Basics Certification, Hackkerank

DP-203 (Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Engineer Associate)

AZ-104 (Microsoft Certified: Azure Administrator Associate)

PL 300 (Microsoft Certified: Power BI Data Analyst Associate)